Let‘s be honest — I’m sure we‘ve all done something a little dishonest in our lives — maybe copying someone’s work, borrowing some money from a friend and not paying them back or being given too much change in a shop and keeping quiet about it.
老实说——我敢肯定我们在生活中都做过一些有点不诚实的事情——也许是抄袭别人的作业，向朋友借了钱却不还，或者在商店里收到多找的零钱却默不作声。
Or maybe I‘m wrong, maybe you’re a good, upstanding citizen who believes that honesty is the best policy.
又或许我错了，也许你是一个优秀、正直的公民，相信诚实才是最好的处事原则。
This proverb, ‘honesty is the best policy‘, was written back in the 1700s by American statesman, Benjamin Franklin.
“诚实才是上策”这句谚语是美国政治家本杰明·富兰克林在18世纪写的。
We may agree that owning up to our mistakes and behaving in a genuine and decent way, is the right way to lead our lives.
我们可能都认同，承认自己的错误，以真诚的和正直的方式行事，才是正确的生活方式。
But is there something in our human nature that makes us unscrupulous?
但我们的人性中是否存在一些东西让我们变得肆无忌惮呢？
For example, in some shops and car parks you can find an honesty box — a box where you pay for something by putting money in it — but it relies on you putting the right amount of cash in.
例如，在一些商店和停车场，你会看到一个诚信箱——一个你通过往里面放钱来支付东西费用的箱子——但这依赖于你放入正确数额的现金。
This relies on people being honest and not trying to cheat but it does provide a temptation to get away with not paying the full amount.
这依赖于人们的诚实，不试图欺骗，但这确实提供了一种诱惑，让人有可能不付全款就蒙混过关。
Philip Graves, a psychologist, and author of the book Consumerology, suggests that this temptation is part of our evolution.
心理学家、《消费学》一书的作者菲利普·格雷夫斯认为，这种诱惑是我们进化的一部分。
He says: “We have evolved with the capacity to be dishonest.
他说：“我们在进化过程中具备了不诚实的能力。
It‘s part of our evolutionary psychological make up — because if we gain an advantage over the people around us, we have a greater chance of surviving.”
这是我们进化心理构成的一部分——因为如果我们比周围的人获得优势，我们就有更大的生存机会。”
So why do we place such importance on being honest if we benefit from being dishonest?
那么，如果我们能从不诚实中获益，为什么我们还如此重视诚实呢？
It’s because it is selfish behaviour — which other members of our social group won‘t like.
这是因为不诚实是一种自私的行为——我们社会群体中的其他成员不会喜欢这种行为。
If everybody acted selfishly and dishonestly all the time, the world would be a very unpleasant place.
如果每个人一直都自私地、不诚实地行事，这个世界将会变得非常令人不快。
As Philip Graves says: “There is a balance to strike between the extent to which we can feather our own nest, so to speak, and the risk of being ostracised by the group.”
正如菲利普·格雷夫斯所说：“可以这么说，在我们中饱私囊的程度和被群体排斥的风险之间，需要找到一个平衡点。”
So, for societies to work together we need to trust each other and therefore we need to be honest.
所以，为了让社会能够协同运转，我们需要相互信任，因此我们需要诚实。
Being trustworthy with money is of course crucial for an economy to survive and there are laws to protect us from dishonest practices like corruption and fraud.
在金钱方面值得信赖对于经济的生存当然至关重要，而且有法律保护我们免受像贪污和欺诈这样不诚实的行为的侵害。
But being honest with words is another matter; saying what we think to someone can get us into hot water.
但在言语上诚实则是另一回事；对别人说出我们的想法可能会让我们陷入麻烦。
However a new anonymous messaging app has been designed that lets anyone with a link to your profile to send you a message without knowing who it’s from.
然而，一款新的匿名信息应用程序被设计出来了，它让任何有你个人资料链接的人都可以给你发信息，而你却不知道信息来自谁。
The app now has 300 million users which perhaps indicates how honest we really like to be — but in all honesty, do you want to know what people think about you?
这款应用现在有3亿用户，这也许表明了我们到底有多希望自己诚实——但说实在的，你想知道人们是怎么看待你的吗？
Is honesty always the best policy?!
诚实真的永远是上策吗？！